yesmagazine.org 2018-07-30

# Privacy Policy — YES! Magazine

YES! Media operates a website, found at www.yesmagazine.org and store.yesmagazine.org; operates several Facebook pages and groups; delivers newsletters and other content via email; and makes the same or similar content available to mobile users. Our Privacy Policy applies when you use any of these Services. It describes the kinds of information we may gather when you use the Services, how we use your information, when we might disclose your information, and how you can manage your information.

Our policy does not apply to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link or who may link to us. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies of third party websites.

By using our Services, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy, including our use of cookies and similar online tools. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Services.

[Click here for our donor privacy and transparency policies](https://www.yesmagazine.org/about/donor-privacy-and-transparency-policies). 

## What information do we gather about you?

The information we gather falls into two categories:

  1.  Personal information you voluntarily supply when you subscribe, order, complete a survey, or provide your email address and
  2. Tracking information collected as you navigate through our site.

#### Paid Products and Services

While our website is free, we do sell products such as subscriptions and back issues. To enable the purchase of these and other products, we collect and store billing information. This information will only be shared with third parties who perform tasks required to complete the transaction. Examples of this include fulfilling orders and processing credit card payments.

#### Reader Surveys, Reader Panels and Market Research

YES! may collect personal information from readers in connection with voluntary surveys. Data may be collected on our website, on the phone, or via email. Readers are primarily contacted via email, with links to online surveys, but may occasionally be contacted by telephone or mail. All survey data is reported and/or used in aggregate form only, and no personally identifiable information is released. 

#### Aggregate Information Collected Through Technology

  * **Cookies and Other Technologies**  
As is standard practice on many websites, YES! uses “cookies” and other technologies for legitimate interests to recognize you to help us understand which parts of our website are the most popular, where our visitors are going and how much time they spend there. We use Google analytics to do some of this collection. We reserve the right to change the vendors who provide us with usage data. You have the option to  **opt-out of Google Analytics cookies altogether**  here:  [ https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en ](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

We also use Disqus as our commenting system, which can be used by your choice. Diqus may also use cookies and has a separate privacy policy: <https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy>.

  * **IP Addresses**  
We use the IP address log in an aggregate fashion to track access to our site. Log data is used in aggregate to analyze usage of our website.

## What do we do with the information we gather about you?

#### Statistical Analysis

YES! may perform statistical, demographic and marketing analyses of subscribers, and their subscribing and purchasing patterns, for marketing and customer service purposes 

#### Email Newsletters 

If you choose to receive them, YES! will periodically send you email newsletters. 

YES! complies fully with the federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003. We will not share, sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your email address. If you feel you have received an email from us in error, please contact yesnewsletters [at] yesmagazine.org.

#### Email Promotions

If you provide your email address as a customer or newsletter subscriber, YES! reserves the right to send you promotional emails about products and services offered by YES!, fundraising campaigns, and occasional events that YES! participates in. You may opt out of these emails at any time. 

#### Account and Service-Related Email

YES! reserves the right to send you email relating to your account status. This includes order confirmations, renewal/expiration notices, notices of account problems, other transactional emails and notifications about major changes to our website and/or to our Privacy Policy. If you would like to stop all communications from YES! please email customercare [at] yesmagazine.org with your name, address, and, if you get the magazine, your subscriber number (found on the mailing label of your magazine), and request that we hold all contact. If you have registered for online discussions or other services, you may receive email specific to your participation in those activities.

#### Survey Email

We may send you an email inviting you to participate in user surveys. User surveys greatly help us to improve our Web site and magazine and any information we obtain in such surveys will not be shared with third parties.

#### Emails From You

If you send us email, you should be aware that information disclosed in email may not be secure or encrypted and thus may be available to others. We suggest that you exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal or confidential information via email. Please do not send credit card information via email. This is better conveyed via a secure form on our website or over the phone to our Customer Service representatives. We will use your email address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

#### Email This Article Feature

YES! readers may use this feature to send links to articles to others through email. The email address(es) that you supply to this service will only be used to send the requested article

## With whom do we share the information we gathered?

YES! will not sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your email address without your permission.

If you are a print subscriber to YES! magazine and subscribed either by mail, phone or online, we may exchange or rent your name and mailing address (but not your email address) with other like-minded organizations through direct mail. If you prefer that we do not share this information, you may opt-out at any time—see opt-out instructions below under “Print Promotions.”

#### Service Providers

We contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf, including credit-card and billing processing, shipping, website analytics, and for remarketing or to advertise YES! products across the internet. We provide these companies only with the information they need to perform their services. These service providers are restricted from using this data in any way other than to provide services for YES!, and they may not share or resell this data.

## How to opt out from receiving newsletters and promotional offers

#### Email Newsletters

YES! offers several email newsletters. If you no longer wish to receive a newsletter, click the “unsubscribe” link located near the bottom of each newsletter. Clicking this link will instantly opt you out of all YES! emails, but you will be presented with the option of re-subscribing to any newsletters or communications that you still wish to receive. If you take no action, you will stay unsubscribed from everything. 

#### Email Promotions

If, at any time, you prefer not to receive marketing or fundraising emails from us, click the “unsubscribe” link located near the bottom of one of these emails. Clicking this link will instantly opt you out of all YES! emails, but you will be presented with the option of re-subscribing to any newsletters or communications that you still wish to receive. If you take no action, you will stay unsubscribed from everything. 

If you experience difficulty with the unsubscribe process, feel free to contact us at yesnewsletters [at] yesmagazine.org and provide your email address along with the name/type of the emails from which you would like to unsubscribe.

#### Print Promotions

If you prefer that we do not share your address, you may opt-out of 3rd party mailings by logging in to your account (<https://store.yesmagazine.org/my-account/>), clicking the “manage” button next to a recent subscription, and choosing that option. You can also opt-out by emailing customer service. Email us at subs [at] yesmagazine.org, put “don't share my name” in the subject and include in the body your subscriber number and name. If you don't know your subscriber number (found on the address label of the magazine), you will need to include your address as well, so we can correctly identify you.

## Is your information protected?

#### Data Security

We use reasonable precautions to protect our users' personal information and to store it securely. Sensitive information that is transmitted to us online (such as a credit card number) is 256-bit encrypted and is transmitted to us securely.  If you are not comfortable sending your credit card information over the Internet, please call the YES! office (1-800-937-4451), or print the page and FAX (206-842-5208) or mail it to us.  (284 Madrona Way NE Suite 116, Bainbridge Island, WA 98110)

Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard your information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. To further protect your data, we recommend that you use complex passwords for your accounts with us and for accounts with third parties that you link to any of your accounts with us. Please do not use the same passwords you use for your account with us for other services or share your password with unauthorized people. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please immediately notify us in accordance with the “Contact Us” section below.

#### Data Retention 

How Long We Keep Your Information For: We keep your information for no longer than is necessary. We will retain your information for any period required by law. Where we are not under a legal obligation to retain your information, we will determine what is necessary by reference to the lawful basis for processing set out above and our legitimate interests.

If you have any questions about how long we keep your information, please contact us. ****

### Users in the EEA and Switzerland

_  
If you are a resident of the EEA or Switzerland, the following information applies with respect to personal data collected through your use of our Services._

**  
Purposes of processing and legal basis for processing** : We process personal data consistent with our disclosures in this Privacy Policy. We process personal data on the following legal bases: (1) with your consent; (2) as necessary to perform our agreement to provide Services (such as when you become a Subscriber); and (3) as necessary for our legitimate interests in providing the Services where those interests do not override your fundamental rights and freedoms related to data privacy.

**  
Transfers** : Personal data we collect may be transferred to, and stored and processed in, the United States or any other country in which we or our affiliates or processors maintain facilities. We will ensure that transfers of personal data to a third country or an international organization are subject to appropriate safeguards.

**  
Your Rights** : You are entitled to the rights under Chapter III of the EU General Data Protection Regulation or Section 2 of the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection with respect to the processing of your personal data, which include the right to access and correct and to request erasure of personal data.  **To exercise these rights, contact[[email protected]](https://www.yesmagazine.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) and provide as complete a description of your request as possible.**

### Children Under 18

We do not intentionally collect any personally identifiable information from individuals under the age of 18, with the exception of our national student writing program and we will make every effort to delete any details of such users where a parent or guardian has informed us that these details have been collected. To participate in our national student writing program (also known as exemplary essays) students under 18 must submit written parental consent.

### Who We Are:  Contact Us

**YES! Magazine**

**284 Madrona Way NE #116**

**Bainbridge Island, WA 98110**

**Phone: 206 842-0216**

**Email:[[email protected]](https://www.yesmagazine.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)**

For help with accounts, email: [[email protected]](https://www.yesmagazine.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

* * *

### _Changes to This Policy_

_This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page so you should check here from time to time._
